We did it. Putting the work between us and that includes you,
لقد فعلناها. بطرح العمل بيننا وبما في ذلك أنتم،
we managed to get our Wikipedia crawler up and running.
نجحنا في الحصول على متتبع ويكبيديا وتشغيله.
Let's review how we did it.
دعونا نراجع كيف فعلنا ذلك.
The very first thing we did was to try out clicking the wikipedia links by hand.
أول شيء قمنا به كان محاولة النقر على روابط Wikipedia باليد.
We came to understand what we were trying to achieve with our program.
وتمكنا من فهم ما كنا نحاول تحقيقه باستخدام برنامجنا.
Next, we did some learning.
بعد ذلك، تعلمنا بعض الأمور.
We found out about the structure of the input data HTML,
عرفنا عن بنية بيانات إدخال HTML،
and we researched useful Python packages that would help us process it.
وبحثنا عن حزم Python جديدة التي ستساعدنا في معالجتها.
Next, we designed a program,
بعد ذلك، صممنا البرنامج،
but without coding it up yet.
لكن بدون ترميزه بعد.
We made decisions about the kind of loop to use,
اتخذنا قرارات بشأن نوع التكرار الحلقي الذي سنستخدمه،
the data structures that we would need,
وبنية البيانات التي سنحتاج إليها،
and decided the steps we would perform and their order.
وقررنا الخطوات التي سنقوم بها وترتيبها.
There was also a specific extra item that's important if you're interacting with the Web.
يوجد أيضًا عنصر إضافي محدد هام إذا كنتم تتعاملون مع صفحة ويب.
We slowed the program down to avoid it being a nuisance.
أبطأنا البرنامج حتى لا يكون مصدرًا للإزعاج.
Only after all that work did we start writing code.
وبعد القيام بكل هذا العمل، بدأنا في كتابة الكود.
Charlie wrote the continue_crawl function that controls the while loop,
كتبت تشارلي دالة continue_crawl التي تتحكم في التكرار الحلقي while،
and laid out the main steps inside of that while loop.
ووضعت الخطوات الأساسية داخل التكرار الحلقي While.
In the process, she actually ended up planning a separate function, find_first_link.
أثناء العملية، انتهت بالفعل من تخطيط دالة منفصلة، find_first_link..
She worked out what it would need to do,
وعملت على ما يجب القيام به،
but not actually how to do it.
ولكن ليس على كيفية القيام به بالفعل.
I was the one who wrote the find_first_link function following Charlie's specification.
كنت الشخص الذي كتب دالة find_first_link متبعًا مواصفات تشارلي.
I also tested everything to make sure that code
واختبرت أيضًا كل شيء للتأكد من أن الكود
worked on a variety of Wikipedia pages.
عمل على مجموعة متنوعة من صفحات Wikipedia.
I iterated on the code that I had written
كررت الكود الذي كنت قد كتبته
in order to make it work on every Wikipedia page that I found.
لكي أجعله يعمل على كل صفحات Wikipedia التي وجدتها.
You can use these bullet points and
يمكنكم استخدام النقاط المدرجة
this example to help next time you're writing a program.
وهذا المثال لكي يساعدكم المرة التالية التي تكتبون فيها برنامجًا.
Depending on the work you're doing,
ونبعًا لنوع العمل الذي تقوم به،
you might need to change the order,
قد تحتاج إلى تغيير الترتيب،
or repeat the step more than once.
أو تكرار الخطوة أكثر من مرة.
These are basic steps that you'll come back to again and again when you're programming.
هذه هي الخطوات الأساسية التي سترجع إليها مرارًا وتكرارًا عند البرمجة.